# Priyadarshini K

Research Scientist, Sony Research priyadarshini.kumari@sony.com https://priyadarshini-k.com/

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Multimodal learning, Graph representation learning, Natural language processing, Knowledge graph embedding and reasoning, Data-efficient machine learning - Active and transfer learning

My research aims to create scalable, data-efficient models that continuously learn, adapt, and ensure interpretability in decision processes. My work has explored the applicability of these models in various domains, including biomedical research for scientific discoveries, the design of recommendation systems, and the development of multimodal perception models encompassing vision, speech, and olfactory inputs.

## APPOINTMENTS

- Research Scientist, Sony Research Sept 2021 - present

- Project Research Engineer, IIT Bombay Aug 2015 - Dec 2015

- Risk Analyst, CitiCorp Service India Ltd, Pune Jul 2013 - Oct 2014

## **EDUCATION**

#### Indian Institute of Technology Bombay

2016 - 2021

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Label-Efficient Distance Metric Learning

Advisor: Prof. Subhasis Chaudhuri and Prof. Siddhartha Chaudhuri

#### Indian Institute of Technology Bombay

2011 - 2013

Masters in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Multimodal Rendering of 3D Objects at Different Scales

# AWARDS AND HONORS

- TCS Ph.D. Research Fellowship for 4 years (2016 2019)
- Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finalist, 2019
- Department Excellence in Teaching Assistantship (TA), 2018
- Recipient of MHRD PhD Fellowship 2016
- Recipient of MHRD Post-Graduate fellowship 2011

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Uchenna Akujuobi, **Priyadarshini K**, Jihun Choi, Samy Badreddine, Kana Maruyama, Sucheendra K. Palaniappan and Tarek R. Besold. Using the dynamics of discovery: A temporal graph-based hierarchical approach to automated hypothesis generation (under submission)
- 2. Daniel Shin, Gao Pei, **Priyadarshini K**, and Tarek Besold. Optimizing Learning Across Multimodal Transfer Features for Modeling Olfactory Perception, SIGKDD Multimodal Workshop 2023
- 3. **Priyadarshini K** and Michael Spranger. Perceptual metrics for odorants: learning from non-expert similarity feedback using machine learning (under submission)
- 4. Tanoy Debnath, Samy Badreddine, **Priyadarshini K** and Michael Spranger. Comparing molecular representations, e-nose signals, and other featurization, for learning to smell aroma molecules, PLOS One, 2023
- 5. **Priyadarshini K** and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Enhancing Haptic Distinguishability of Surface Materials with Boosting Technique. IEEE Haptics Symposium 2022
- 6. **Priyadarshini K**, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, Vivek Borkar and Subhasis Chaudhuri. A unified batch selection policy for active metric learning, ECML-PKDD, 2021
- 7. **Priyadarshini K**, Ritesh Goru, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Batch Decorrelation for Active Metric Learning, IJCAI-PRICAI, 2020.
- 8. **Priyadarshini K**, Siddhartha Chaudhuri, and Subhasis Chaudhuri. PerceptNet: Learning Perceptual Similarity of Haptic Textures in Presence of Unorderable Triplets. IEEE World Haptics Conference (IEEE WHC), 2019.
- 9. **Priyadarshini K** and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Haptic Rendering of Thin, Deformable Objects with Spatially Varying Stiffness. EuroHaptics, 2016.
- 10. Praseedha K., Sreeni K., **Priyadarshini K**, Subhasis Chaudhuri. Combined Hapto-Visual and Auditory Rendering of Cultural Heritage Objects. Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) e-Heritage Workshop, 2014.
- 11. **Priyadarshini K**, Sreeni K.G. and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Scalable Rendering of Variable Density Point Cloud Data. IEEE World Haptics Conference (IEEE WHC), 2013.
- 12. Sreeni K.G., **Priyadarshini K**, A.K. Praseedha and Subhasis Chaudhuri. Haptic Rendering of Cultural Heritage Objects at Different Scales. EuroHaptics, 2012.

## BOOK CHAPTER

Subhasis Chaudhuri and **Priyadarshini Kumari**. Cultural Heritage Object: Bringing Them Alive Through Virtual Touch, *Diqital Hampi: Preserving Indian Cultural Heritage*, Springer, 2018.

# **MASTERS THESIS**

#### Multimodal Rendering of 3D Objects at Different Scales

- Summary: Developed a multimodal rendering technique to synthesize a combined *hapto-visual-auditory* perceptual experience of interaction with 3D model of objects. The goal of this project was to provide access to the heritage objects to visually-impaired people.
- **Domains involved:** Image Processing, Computer Graphics, Computer Vision, Haptic Signal Processing.

#### PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Senior program chair for WiML un-workshop @ ICML 2023
- Area chair for WiML workshop @ NeurIPS 2022
- Session chair for ECML-PKDD 2021
- Group mentor @GHC 2022
- Reviewer @ IJCAI, ECML-PKDD, Neurips, ISMAR, IEEE WHC, IEEE Haptics Symposium, Euro-Haptics

#### **Talks**

- August 2023: @ Sony Tech Talk, Virtual
- August 2023: @ Multimodal SIGKDD 2023, Longbeach, CA
- July 2023: @ WiML Un-workshop ICML 2023, Hawaii
- July 2023: @ 3rd Nobel Turing Workshop, CMU Pittsburgh PA
- May 2023: @ Sony Journal Club, Virtual
- March 2022: @ IEEE Haptics Symposium 2022, Virtual
- Jan 2022: @ Sony Journal Club, Virtual
- October 2021: @ PhD defense, IIT Bombay
- July 2021: @ Sony, Tokyo
- September 2021: @ ECML-PKDD 2021, Virtual
- March 2021: @ Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship, Bangalore
- January 2021: @ IJCAI 2020, Virtual (older talks not listed)

## **TEACHING**

Wavelet
Computer Vision
Statistical Signal Analysis
Digital Signal Processing
Signals and System
Communication Lab

[Spring 2020]
[Spring 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018]
[Fall 2019]
[Spring 2019]
[Fall 2017, Fall 2018]
[Fall 2016]